<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oxygenxml.com/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/dbsvg.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    version="5.0">
    <title>Action Service</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>Section1 Title</title>
        <para>The action service is destined to integrate with JavaFX event handling. The
            fundamental properties of a JavaFX event are that events have a
                <emphasis>type</emphasis>, <emphasis>source</emphasis>, and a
                <emphasis>target</emphasis>. The action service will respond to events by providing
            a possibly empty set of actions that are appropriate for individual events.</para>
        <para>The action service will interact with the Authentication and Authorization service and
            the Preferences service to populate actions. </para>
        <para>A dispatch chain could start with Action Service Dispatcher->Authentication &amp;
            Authorization->Drools</para>
        <para>The Action Service Dispatcher should not run on the event thread. Maybe should have
            two dispatchers, one on the event thread, and one on the Action Service Dispatcher. </para>
        <para>Have objects that implement an interface for user selection of actions. Keep this in a
            weak set. </para>
        <para>Actions should use JavaFX tasks for the underlying processing. </para>
        <para/>
        <para>An inline SVG graphic:  <inlinemediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata>
                    <svg:svg xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="3cm" height="3cm"
                        viewBox="0 0 400 400">
                        <svg:g style="fill-opacity:0.7; stroke:black; stroke-width:0.1cm;">
                            <svg:circle cx="6cm" cy="2cm" r="100" style="fill:red;"
                                transform="translate(0,50)"/>
                            <svg:circle cx="6cm" cy="2cm" r="100" style="fill:blue;"
                                transform="translate(70,150)"/>
                            <svg:circle cx="6cm" cy="2cm" r="100" style="fill:green;"
                                transform="translate(-70,150)"/>
                        </svg:g>
                    </svg:svg>                    
                </imagedata>
            </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject>
        </para>
        <para/>
        <sect2>
            <title>Action Service Integration</title>
            <para>The action service will integrate with the JavaFX event model via use of Event
                Filters, so that the actions will be available to the target event handler.</para>
            <para/>
            <sect3>
                <title>Asynchronous Action Determination</title>
                <para>Computing all allowable actions on the FX event thread could make event
                    handling sluggish. The actions need to be computed asynchronously, and the
                    actions made available to the event handler when the action computation is
                    complete. Maybe consume the event, and then restart an event when the actions
                    become available?</para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Event type extensions</title>
            <para>The JavaFX event model has event types that correspond to user action that occur
                once the application has been initialized. However, some potential actions need to
                be determined when opening a window, (such as what actions should be available
                within which menus). To enable the Action Service to identify these actions, we add
                the following event types to the standard JavaFX event types: </para>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Menu initialization event</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Context added event</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
</article>
